<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hierarchical Classification | Sansa's Site</title><link>https://summmeer.github.io/tag/hierarchical-classification/</link><atom:link href="https://summmeer.github.io/tag/hierarchical-classification/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Hierarchical Classification</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://summmeer.github.io/media/icon_hu4465e7aec766cd42246149649a25868d_28750_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>Hierarchical Classification</title><link>https://summmeer.github.io/tag/hierarchical-classification/</link></image><item><title>Dynamic Product Categorization for Multiple Domain</title><link>https://summmeer.github.io/project/productcate/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://summmeer.github.io/project/productcate/</guid><description>&lt;p>Product categorization is to assign a product with a suitable category, which is usually organized in a predefined taxonomy. As e-commerce platforms developing different business lines, a special but challenging categorization scenario emerges, where there are multiple domain-specific category taxonomies and each of them evolves dynamically over time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In order to unify the categorization process and jointly utilize the cross-domain data, we propose a two-stage taxonomy-agnostic framework that relies solely on calculating the semantic relatedness between product titles and category names in the vector space.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, pure vector matching may fall for the surface form of text, and we thus further leverage the universal “knowledge” across different business domains to complement textual semantics. We design a heuristic retrieval strategy and pretrain a contrastive ranking model with the help of “concept”, which resembles the shared keyword knowledge cross domains.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our comprehensive experiments show that our method outperforms existing sophisticated approaches quantitatively and efficiently on dynamical multi-domain taxonomies.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>